The Nemours Papers: Series 3 of the Du Pont Family Papers 1831 (1915-1935) 1947
Special Collections, Washington and Lee University
- Printed Materials
  - General
    - Souvenir program of the coronation of George VI and Queen Elizabeth of England 1937 (Box-folder 18:4)
    - "American Views-News from Germany" 1940 (Box-folder 18:5)
    - Pamphlet on lip-reading 1914-1915 (Box-folder 18:6)
    - "Electricity in Gynecology," Charles B. Graf, M.D., reprint from The Eclective Review 1914 July (Box-folder 18:7)
    - Banking and Trust Laws of the State of Florida J.M. Lee Comptroller 1933 (Box-folder 18:8)
    - Visitor's guide to Fontainebleu 1936 (Box-folder 18:9)
  - Clippings
    - Clippings re: the United States government's suit against DuPont de Nemours Co. 1909 (Box-folder 18:10)
    - Clippings re: politics 1916 (Box-folder 18:11)
    - Clipping about the annual outings of the duPont powder mill workers 1922-1923 (Box-folder 18:12)
    - Clipping re: christening of the yacht Nenemoosha 1922 (Box-folder 18:13)
    - Clippings re: Jessie Ball duPont's gift to the home economics departments of Delaware high schools 1922 (Box-folder 18:14)
    - Clippings re: United States and Delaware politics 1922-1924 (Box-folder 18:15)
    - Clippings re: Christmas charity distributed by AId 1925 (Box-folder 19:1)
    - Clippings re: the wedding and divorce of Alicia Armory Maddox 1922-1926 (Box-folder 19:2)
    - Clipping re: the wedding of Elizabeth Frances duPont n.d. (Box-folder 19:3)
    - "We hired the money-They hired the soldiers," Lord Beaverbrook, reprint from the Daily Express n.d. (Box-folder 19:4)
    - Miscellaneous clippings relating, among other topics, to Alicia duPont Glendening 1935-1936, n.d. (Box-folder 19:5)
    - Miscellaneous clippings re: society news and other topics 1936, n.d. (Box-folder 19:6)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings on radium and radium ore 1913 (Box-folder 19:7)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings re: the lawsuit Philip F. duPont et al. v. Pierre S. duPont et al. 1915-1916 (Box-folder 19:8-9)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings about Alfred I. duPont's involvement in a slander suit; purchase of the Delaware Trust Company 1916 (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings about Alfred I. duPont, his business affairs, and his involvement in Delaware politics 1918 (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings about the donation of a bust of President Tyler to the State Capitol in Richmond, Virginia; society news; donations to the State Welfare Home in Delaware n.d. (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings with social news; also about charities distributed by Alfred I. duPont; the donation of a bust of President Tyler to the State Capitol in Richmond, Virginia 1925-1935 (Box 2)
    - Scrapbook containing clippings about the death of Alfred I. duPont and the construction of his memorial; banking; social news 1931-1935 (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - A5 Adair, Henry (Box-folder 20:1)
  - A8 Airplanes (Box-folder 20:2)
  - A10 Andrews Family (Box-folder 20:3)
  - B4 Baker Family (Box-folder 20:4-5)
  - B4.5 Ball, Edward (Box-folder 20:6-10)
  - B5 Ball Family (Box-folder 20:11-41)
  - B6 Barrick Family (Carolyn Martin Barrick) (Box-folder 20:42)
  - B7 Baudeny, Victorine E. duPont (Box-folder 20:43)
  - B10 Bennett, Charles, United States Representative from Florida (Box-folder 20:44)
  - B12 Bermingham 1904 (Box-folder 20:45)
  - B15 Black Gates Estates (Box-folder 20:46)
  - B19 Bowley, Elsie and Albert (Box-folder 20:47)
  - Bowley, Elsie and Albert (Box-folder 20:48-52)
  - B21 Bowley, William and wife (Box-folder 21:1)
  - B40 Brandywine Manufacturer's Sunday School (Box-folder 21:2)
  - B70 Bronn Family (Box-folder 21:3)
  - B71 Brown, Reverend E.P. (Box-folder 21:4)
  - B72 Brown, Dr. Thomas (Box-folder 21:5)
  - C1 Cannon Family (Charlotte Lee Cannon, daughter of Maurice duPont Lee) (Box-folder 21:6)
  - C2 Carter Family (Box-folder 21:7)
  - C5 Certeau, Roland (Box-folder 21:8)
  - C8 Chamberlain Family (Box-folder 21:9)
  - C10 Cherry Island (Box-folder 21:10-12)
  - C11 Chevalier, Stuart (Box-folder 21:13)
  - C12 Christ Church, Lancaster County, Virginia (Box-folder 21:14)
  - C14 Christmas Cards (Box-folder 21:15-20)
  - C15 Churches, unidentified (Box-folder 21:21)
  - C15.5 Churches in Virginia (Box-folder 21:22)
  - C16 Churchill, Sir Winston (Box-folder 21:23)
  - C19 Cole, Dr. Fred (Box-folder 21:24)
  - C15.5 Coit, Dr. Thomas (Box-folder 21:25)
  - C20 Cox, Albert (Box-folder 21:26)
  - C25 Crane, Robert Brent (Box-folder 22:1-2)
  - C30 Croquet (Box-folder 22:3-4)
  - D5 Dew, Henry W. and Family (Box-folder 22:5-8)
  - D6 Admiral Dewey 1905 (Box-folder 22:9)
  - D9 Mrs. Diehl (Box-folder 22:10)
  - D10 Ditchley (Box-folder 22:11-12)
  - D15 Dogs (Box-folder 22:13-18)
  - D16 DuBell, Reverend Charles (Box-folder 22:19)
  - D19 duPont, Alexis (son of Eleuthère Irénée duPont) (Box-folder 22:20)
  - duPont, Alfred I. (Box-folder 22:21-42)
  - duPont, Alfred I. (Box-folder 23:1-9)
  - D21 duPont, Alfred Rhett 1940 (Box-folder 23:10)
  - D21.5 duPont, Alfred Victor (Box-folder 23:11)
  - D22 duPont, Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont (Box-folder 23:12)
  - D23 duPont, Anne Cazenove (Box-folder 23:13)
  - D24 duPont cemetery (Box-folder 23:14-15)
  - D26 duPont, Charlotte Shephard Henderson (Box-folder 23:15A)
  - D27 duPont, Eleuthère Irénée (1829-1877, father of AId), includes a glass plate (Box-folder 23:16)
  - D28.5 duPont, Gerald Fitz-Gerald (Box-folder 23:17)
  - D30 duPont, Jessie Ball (Box-folder 23:18-28)
  - D40 duPont, Maurice (Box-folder 23:29)
  - D45 duPont, Samuel Francis (Box-folder 23:30)
  - D46 duPont, Sophie Madeleine (Box-folder 23:31)
  - D52 duPont Family, includes unidentified family members (Box-folder 23:32-33)
  - D53 duPont, Jessie Ball Library at the University of the South, Sewanee, Tennessee (Box-folder 23:34)
  - Eaton, Ernest and Family (Box-folder 24:1)
  - E5 Edwards, Mrs. Griffin (Box-folder 24:2)
  - E15 Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box-folder 24:3)
  - E19 Elizabeth II, Queen of England (Box-folder 24:4)
  - E20 Eleutherian Mills, First Office (Box-folder 24:5)
  - E27 Ellerson Family (Box-folder 24:6)
  - E28 Ellett, Ketherine Tyler and Family (Box-folder 24:7-8)
  - E35 Epping Forrest (Box-folder 24:9-20)
    folder 18: Yachts
  - F1 Fairbanks, Avard (sculptor) (Box-folder 24:21-23)
  - F2 Farr, Dr. Lee E. (Box-folder 24:24)
  - F3 Faulkner Family (Ophelia Strum, daughter of Judge Strum) (Box-folder 24:25)
  - F5 Fensom, Elizabeth Ball and Family (Box-folder 24:26)
  - F10 Florida National Bank Board Meeting 1948 (Box-folder 24:27)
  - F18 Francis Alec B. (Box-folder 24:28)
  - F19 Fraser, Frank (Box-folder 24:29)
  - F20 Frick, Colonel E.B. (Box-folder 24:30)
  - G5 Gaines, Dr. Francis P. and Family (Box-folder 24:31)
  - G6 Gentieu, Pierre (Box-folder 24:32)
  - G7 Glasgow Family (Box-folder 24:33-34)
  - G9 Glendening, Alicia Maddox (Box-folder 24:35-38)
  - G9 Glendening, Alicia Armory Maddox (Box-folder 25:1-5)
  - G10 Glendening Family (Box-folder 25:6-8)
  - G20 Gresham Family (Box-folder 25:9-15)
  - H4.5 Haffey Family (Box-folder 25:16)
  - H5 Hagley Powder Mill Area (Box-folder 25:17)
  - H5.5 Haile, Ella G. (Box-folder 25:18-20)
  - H6 Admiral Halsey (Box-folder 25:21)
  - H6.5 Hansen, Mrs. Knut E. (Box-folder 25:22)
  - H7 Hardwicke, Dr. Charles (Box-folder 25:23-24)
  - H7.1 Harding, Diller and Family (Box-folder 25:25)
  - H7.4 Henderson, Robert (Box-folder 25:26)
  - H7.5 Henley, Mason Tyler and Family (Box-folder 25:27)
  - H8 Hiebler, Madeleine and Family (Box-folder 25:28-32)
  - H10 Hollins College (Box-folder 25:33-34)
  - H12 Horses (Box-folder 25:35-37)
  - H14 Hotel The Ambassador (Box-folder 25:38)
  - H15 Houses, unidentified (Box-folder 25:39-44)
  - H20 Huidekoper Family (Box-folder 25:45-48)
  - H30 Hurley, Patrick and Ruth (Box-folder 25:49)
  - J5 Jarrett Family (Box-folder 25:50)
  - J10 Jesse, Lelia Carter (Box-folder 25:51)
  - J11 Jessup Family (Box-folder 25:52)
  - J15 Johnson, John G. (Box-folder 25:53)
  - K5 Kellogg Family (Box-folder 25:54)
  - K10 Klatt, Emil H. and Family (Box-folder 25:55)
  - L1 Landrum Family (Betty Huidekoper Landrum) (Box-folder 25:56)
  - L3 Lee, Maurice duPont and Family (Box-folder 25:57)
  - L3.5 Lee, Reverend Baker P. (Box-folder 26:1)
  - L4 Lee, Marguerite (Box-folder 26:2)
  - L5 Lee, Maurice duPont jr. and Maurice duPont Lee III (Box-folder 26:3-4)
  - L6 Leggieden School, Scotland (Box-folder 26:5)
  - L8 Licks, Olga and Family (Box-folder 26:6)
  - L15 Lorand, Dr. Arnold (Box-folder 26:7)
  - M3 Mahoney Family (Box-folder 26:8)
  - M4 Martin Family (Box-folder 26:9)
  - M5 Mattingly, E. (Treasurer at Washington and Lee University) (Box-folder 26:10)
  - M10 McKinstry, Reverend Arthur (Box-folder 26:11)
  - M30 Mills: Carlin's Mill (Box-folder 26:12)
  - M35 Mills: Ford's Lane (Box-folder 26:13)
  - M40 Mills: Hagley (Box-folder 26:14)
  - M45 Mills: Henry Clay (Box-folder 26:15)
  - M47 Mills: Louviers, Denver, Colorado (Box-folder 26:16)
  - M50 Mills: Perth Amboy, New Jersey (Box-folder 26:17)
  - M55 Mills: Rockville, Maryland (Box-folder 26:18)
  - M65 Mills: Walker's (Siddall's) (Box-folder 26:19)
  - M70 Mills: unidentified (Box-folder 26:20-21)
  - M72 Mitchell, Lester (Box-folder 26:22)
  - M75 unidentified (Box-folder 26:23)
  - M80 Monuments (Box-folder 26:24)
  - M81 Montpelier (Box-folder 26:25)
  - M85 Mott, Kelsey and Family (Box-folder 26:26)
  - N5 Nairn, Ainslie (Box-folder 26:27)
  - N10 Nemours, Gardens and Grounds (Box-folder 26:28)
  - N11 Nemours, Mansion (Box-folder 26:29)
  - N12 Nemours Trading Company (Box-folder 26:30)
  - O25 Oxford Hall (Home of Thomas Ball) (Box-folder 26:31-33)
  - P3 Paine, Thomas B. and Family (Box-folder 26:34)
  - P5 Paguio, Pedro (Box-folder 26:35)
  - P6 Park outing for neighborhood children (Box-folder 26:36)
  - P8 Pearson Family (Box-folder 26:37)
  - P10 Pennington, Robert (Box-folder 26:38)
  - Postcards (Box-folder 26:39-43)
  - R5 Alfred I. duPont Radio Awards (Box-folder 26:44)
  - R10 Reed Family (Box-folder 26:45)
  - R12 Ridgon Family (Box-folder 27:1)
  - R14 Robertson, Mason 1952 (Box-folder 27:2)
  - R15 Ross, Pete and Family (Box-folder 27:3-4)
  - R25 Ruoff, Madeleine duPont Hiebler and Family (Box-folder 27:5-6)
  - S2 St. Joe Paper Company (Box-folder 27:7-10)
  - S3 Schaeffer Family (Box-folder 27:11)
  - S5 Scholarship Award (Box-folder 27:12)
  - S6 Alfred I. duPont School (Box-folder 27:13)
  - S10 Shands, Dr. Alfred R. (Box-folder 27:14-16)
  - S10.5 Sheehy, Reverend Maurice (Box-folder 27:17)
  - S11 Ships (Box-folder 27:18-22)
  - S12 Siegel Family (Box-folder 27:23)
  - S20 Sneed Family (Box-folder 27:24)
  - S24 Snydelaar Family (Box-folder 27:25)
  - S25 Southwood (Box-folder 27:26)
  - S25 Stadler Family (Box-folder 27:27)
  - S27.3 Stephenson, Winifred and Family (Box-folder 27:28)
  - S27.5 Purves-Stewart, Sir James (Box-folder 27:29)
  - S28 Stirling Family (Box-folder 27:30)
  - S29 Stoeckle Family (Box-folder 27:31-32)
  - S29.1 Storrs, Christopher E. (Box-folder 27:33)
  - S29.5 Stokely Family (Box-folder 27:34)
  - S30 Stratford Hall (Box-folder 27:35)
  - S40 Swimming Pool (Box-folder 27:36)
  - T5 Tappahannock, Virginia (Box-folder 27:37)
  - T12 Thompson, Dr. W. Taliaferro (Box-folder 27:38)
  - T13 Thompson Family (Box-folder 27:39-41)
  - T20 Travel Scenes (Box-folder 27:42-50)
  - T20 Travel Scenes (Box-folder 28:1-13)
  - T21 Travel: Trip to Colorado and South Dakota, 1898-1899 (Box-folder 28:14-18)
  - U20 University of the South, Sewanee, Tennessee (Box-folder 28:19)
  - V10 Vehicles: Automobiles (Box-folder 28:20)
  - V18 Vehicles: Gasoline locomotive (Box-folder 28:21)
  - V20 Vehicles: horse-drawn (Box-folder 28:22)
  - V25 Verlaine Family (Box-folder 28:23)
  - V30 Virginia Military Institute: 100th Anniversary Ball (Box-folder 28:24)
  - W2 Ward Family (Box-folder 28:25)
  - W3 Watts Family (Box-folder 28:26)
  - W7 Wharton, Dr. H.M. (Box-folder 28:27)
  - W10 White Eagle, exterior (Box-folder 28:28)
  - W15 White Eagle interior (Box-folder 28:29-30)
  - W16 Whittet, Jean Fraser (Box-folder 28:31)
  - W18 William and Mary, College of (Box-folder 29:1)
  - W19 Williamsburg, Virginia (Box-folder 29:2)
  - W21 Wilson, Dr. Philip D. (Box-folder 29:3)
  - W25 World War I (Box-folder 29:4)
  - W30 Wright, Thomas Ball (Box-folder 29:5)
  - Y8 Yacht Alfred I. duPont (Box-folder 29:6)
  - Y10 Yacht Nenemoosha (Box-folder 29:8-23)
  - Y10.5 Yacht Nenemoosha, construction (Box-folder 29:24)
  - Y11 Yacht Nenemoosha, crew (Box-folder 29:25-26)
  - Y15 Yacht, unidentified (Box-folder 30:1-9)
  - Y20 Yacht S.Y. Alicia (Box-folder 30:10)
  - Z5 Zapffe, Denise duPont (Box-folder 30:11-28)
  - Z6 Zapffe Family (Box-folder 30:29-42)
  - Oversized Photographs
    B5 Ball Family
    D4 Dent Family
    D15 Dogs
    D16 DuBell, Charles and wife
    D18 duPont, Alexis I.
    D19 duPont, Alfred
    D20 duPont, Alfred I.
    D30 duPont, Jessie Ball
    D38 duPont, Lammot
    D42 duPont de Nemours, Samuel
    D44 duPont, Samuel
    D45 duPont, [Admiral] Samuel Francis
    D50 duPont, Victor
    D51 duPont, Victor Marie
    D52 duPont Family members, unidentified
    F25 Friends and acquaintances
    G5 Gaines Family
    G9 Glendening, Alicia Armory Maddox
    G10 Glendening Family
    G18 Grant, Reverend James M.
    H5 Hagley Powder Mill area
    H5.5 Haile, Ella
    H8 Hiebler Family
    H12 Horses "Time O'War"
    J20 Joyeur, Sterling J.
    L2 Lanier, May M.
    L10 Littell, Norman M.
    M3 MacArthur, General Douglas
    M4 Martin, William A.
    M70.5 Mill Workers
    R25 Ruoff Family
    S10 Shands, Dr. Alfred R.
    S24 Southwood
    S31 Stuart, Alfred Irénée
    T13 Thompson Family
    V10 Vehicles: automobiles
    W30 Wright, Thomas Ball
    Y10 Yacht Nenemoosha
    Z5 Zapffe, Denise duPont
    Z6 Zapffe Family
  - B5 Ball Family (Box 4:1)
  - D4 Dent Family (Box 4:2)
  - D16 DuBell, Reverend Charles (Box 4:3)
  - D20 duPont, Alfred I. (Box 4:4-6)
  - D30 duPont, Jessie Ball (Box 4:7)
  - D38 duPont, Lammot (Box 4:8)
  - D42 duPont, Pierre Samuel, de Nemours (Box 4:9)
  - D44 Samuel, father of Pierre Samuel (Box 4:10)
  - D45 duPont, [Admiral] Samuel Francis (Box 4:11)
  - D51 duPont, Victor Marie (Box 5:1)
  - D52 duPont Family, unidentified family members (Box 5:2)
  - F25 Friends and acquaintances (Box 5:3)
  - G5 Gaines, Frank P. and Family (Box 5:4)
  - G9 Glendening, Alicia Armory Maddox (Box 5:5)
  - G10 Glendening Family (Box 5:6)
  - H5 Hagley Area Powder Mill (Box 5:7)
  - H5.5 Maile, Ella (Box 5:8)
  - H12 Horses "Time O'War" (Box 5:9)
  - J20 Joyeur, Sterling J. (Box 5:10)
  - L2 Lanier, May M. (Box 5:11)
  - M3 MacArthur, General Douglas (Box 5:12)
  - M4 Martin Family (Box 5:13)
  - M70.5 Mill workers and Alfred I. duPont (Box 5:14)
  - S10 Shands, Dr. Alfred R. (Box 5:15)
  - S24 Snydelaar Family (Box 5:16)
  - S31 Stuart, Alfred Irenee (Box 5:17)
  - T13 Thompson Family (Box 5:18)
  - V10 Vehicles: Automobiles (Box 5:19)
  - W30 Wright, Thomas Ball (Box 5:20)
  - Y21 Yacht Nenemoosha (Box 5:21)
  - Z5 Zapffe, Denise duPont (Box 5:22)